Christopher Makrides | Software Engineer

About Me

I am a passion driven software engineer who specializes in full stack development. Given my physics/engineering background, I enjoy solving complex mathematical/algorithmic problems and applying that knowledge to my applications. In addition, given my creative/artistic experience, I like to apply unique style to my applications. Big believer in work/life Balance and open/honest communication. I strive to work alongside people who are efficient with their work, effective in completing goals, and have an overall desire to better the world.

Skills

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, Java Libraries and Frameworks - React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Tailwind Database - PostgreSQL, SQL, MongoDB, Mongoose Other - RESTful Routing JSON, Netlify, Heroku

Software Development Projects

December 2021 - PRESENT

Shakn - Social platform for bartenders/cocktail enthusiasts to share and review cocktail recipes

- Utilized MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js to build a MERN decoupled full stack application in 6 days. With full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations.
- Styled the application using Tailwind CSS.
- Tested API routes using Postman to ensure functionality and proper connection to our MongoDB databases.
- Implemented photo upload functionality using Cloudinary API.
- Used token based authentication to log in users to their profiles to save the cocktails they make to their profile.

Cocktail Foundations - Tool for searching and viewing cocktail recipes, in addition to making digital flashcards to study

- Utilized MongoDB, Express, Node.js to build a full stack application in 4 days. With full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations hitting all RESTful API calls.
- Created an application with a mobile-first approach and styled using Styled-Components and CSS3 with flexbox layouts.
- Used Google Authentication to log in users to their profiles and save the recipes they make onto a database.

4 Player Dominoes - Online Browser Dominoes Game

- Leveraged embedded Javascript, CSS3, HTML5, with partials to organize and display the visual aspects.
- Wireframed and planned UI design of application using trello, whimsical, and created icons, logos, game piece images using Adobe PhotoShop.
- Utilized Git control during the production of the application with frequent commits until deployment.
- Implemented Javascript methods and functions using algorithms to run crucial aspects of the game. Such as player placement of dominoes, computer placement of dominoes, and computer AI.

Professional Experience

Schlumberger | Geophysicist | Houston, Texas

09/2014 - 11/2016

- Primary role was performing water velocity correction to the entire survey of geophysical seismic data. This software involved seismic data algorithmic manipulation to process and define geographical areas of interest. Successfully performed the correction and the data was further processed and sold as multimillion dollar assets.
- Achieved "Exceeds Expectations" for overall performance rating, yearly review.
- Acted as first line of quality control, making sure data was properly acquired and stored in data storage which utilizes the google cloud platform.

Udemy | Online Instructor

09/2021

- Carefully design, write, and implement an online course to sell on education websites, with the goal to effectively mentor beginning and aspiring bartenders.
- Used graphics programs such as Adobe Premier, Lightroom, Photoshop, to edit the course content to create compelling course lectures that teach the most relevant and practical information in the field.
- Course has had over 1000 purchases with over 300 positive reviews and continues to grow as use data analytics from google and marketing on Youtube and Instagram.

Electrical Apprentice | Keeley Electric | Maine

04/2019 - 05/2020

- Design and construct fire power distribution systems for commercial clients.
- Installing circuit breaker panels, light fixtures, exit signs, industrial fire alarms.
- Troubleshooting these systems to ensure proper installation while keeping strict adherence to electrical code.
- Successfully installed several systems across Maine.

EDUCATION

General Assembly | Remote

2022

Software Engineering Immersive

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

Bates College | Lewiston, Maine Double Major:

- BS Physics 2014
- BA Theater 2014
- Minor, Mathematics